Michael Alpert collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 7: North American field recordings
  - Leonard Koenig-III, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0457; Alpert 865-866; 1 sound cassette
  - Leonard Koenig-IV, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0458; Alpert 867-868; 1 sound cassette
  - Leonard Koenig-V, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0459; Alpert 869-870; 1 sound cassette
  - Leonard Koenig-VI, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0460; Alpert 871-872; 1 sound cassette
  - Pacific Northwest-I, May 1981, AFC 2017/048: SR0461; Alpert 873-874; 1 sound cassette
  - Pacific Northwest-II; Ronnie on Yiddish Dances, May 1981-March 30, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0462; Personnel: Ronnie.; Alpert 875-876; 1 sound cassette
  - Julian Rep Tape-Ethelbert, etc., undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0465; Personnel: Julian Kytasty.; Alpert 881; 1 sound cassette
  - Andy Statman at Symphony Space; Kapelye at Symphony Space, March 4, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0473; Personnel: Andy Statman, Klezmer Orchestra.; Recording location: Symphony Space.; Alpert 896-897; 1 sound cassette
  - YUGO Program and MJA Tunes, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0487; Alpert 921-922; 1 sound cassette
  - KlezKamp, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0490; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: KlezKamp.; Alpert 941-942; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon-KlezKamp, December 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0491; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: KlezKamp.; Alpert 943; 1 sound cassette
  - Bella Gottesman; Gottesman-Rymer, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0494; Personnel: Bella Gottesman.; Alpert 947-948; 1 sound cassette
  - Gila I, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0496; Personnel: Gila Flam, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 951-952; 1 sound cassette
  - Gila II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0497; Personnel: Gila Flam, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 953-954; 1 sound cassette
  - Lorin Sklamberg-I, May 6, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0499; Personnel: Lorin Sklamberg, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 957; 1 sound cassette
  - Lorin Sklamberg-I; Lorin Sklamberg-II, May 6, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0500; Personnel: Lorin Sklamberg, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 958-959; 1 sound cassette
  - George Caba, Buffalo Gap, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0501; Personnel: George Caba.; Alpert 960-961; 1 sound cassette
  - Turski Nardni Pesni; George Caba Songs, July 18, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0502; Personnel: George Caba.; Alpert 962-963; 1 sound cassette
  - An Afternoon with George Caba and Friends, February 27, 1994, AFC 2017/048: SR0503; Personnel: George Caba.; Alpert 964-965; 1 sound cassette
  - An Afternoon with George Caba and Friends-II, February 27, 1994, AFC 2017/048: SR0504; Personnel: George Caba.; Alpert 966-967; 1 sound cassette
  - George Caba, August 10, 1994, AFC 2017/048: SR0505; Personnel: George Caba, Michael Alpert, Nadja Gemmel.; Recording location: Harrisburg, PA.; Alpert 968-969; 1 sound cassette
  - George Caba, January 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0506; Personnel: George Caba, CP, ML, LB, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 970; 1 sound cassette
  - George Caba and Friends, January 11, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0507; Personnel: George Caba, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 971-972; 1 sound cassette
  - Af Shabes in Fresno-I, July 1, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0508; Personnel: Joel Rubin, Stu Brotman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Fresno, CA.; Alpert 973-974; 1 sound cassette
  - Af Shabes in Fresno-II; 78s from Kurt and Lori via Joel, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0509; Personnel: Joel Rubin, Stu Brotman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Fresno, CA.; Alpert 975-976; 1 sound cassette
  - Jack Kugelmass and Jonathan Boyarin, Yizker-Bikher, November 25, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0514; Alpert 984-985; 1 sound cassette
  - Kapelye, November 18, 1979, AFC 2017/048: SR0524; Recording location: Temple Emanu-El, Providence, RI.; Alpert 1000-1001; 1 sound cassette
  - Kapelye on Prairie Home Companion; Musica en Mexico, July 1980-December 11, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0525; Recording location: Fitzgerald Theater, St. Paul, MN; Alpert 1002-1003; 1 sound cassette
  - BRJCC Sat night, June 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0527; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Joel Rubin, Lauren Brody, Ben Bazyler, Bronya Sakina, Henry Sapoznik.; Recording location: BRJCC.; Alpert 1006-1007; 1 sound cassette
  - Buffalo on the Roof-Discussion, July 21, 1992, AFC 2017/048: SR0534; Alpert 1018-1019; 1 sound cassette
  - A Yid Fun LA, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0544; Alpert 1039-1040; 1 sound cassette
  - Klezfest 2 Clarinet Workshop; Klezfest 2 Folksongs Workshop, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0545; Alpert 1041-1042; 1 sound cassette
  - Klezfest SPb, Sofia Fima Arkady, 2004, AFC 2017/048: SR0546; Personnel: Arkady Gendler.; Alpert 1043; 1 minidisc
  - Klezfest SPb, Sofia Fima Arkady, 2004, AFC 2017/048: SR0547; Personnel: Arkady Gendler.; Alpert 1044; 1 minidisc
  - Vos hot lib, December 15, 2002, AFC 2017/048: SR0551; Alpert 1048; 1 minidisc
  - Adam Geldman, March 2, 2007, AFC 2017/048: SR0552; Personnel: Adam Geldman.; Alpert 1049; 1 minidisc
  - LA Victor Jara, 1974-1975, AFC 2017/048: SR0595; Alpert 1092-1093; 1 sound cassette
  - Bora Gajicki-Serbian Accordion; Folk, Pennywhistlers, Dylan, Bulgarian Bush, 1975-1976, AFC 2017/048: SR0596; Recording location: Long Beach, CA.; Alpert 1094-1095; 1 sound cassette
  - Conjunto, Jarocho, August 1977, AFC 2017/048: SR0597; Personnel: José Gutierrez (harp), Bobby Chagoya (requinto), César Ramón (jarana), Zocorro Aguíniga (dancer), Dan Sheehy (presenter), others named in recording.; Recording location: Hollywood, CA.; Alpert 1096-1097; 1 sound cassette
  - Shashmaaam, July 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0599; Recording location: Harborfest, NYC; Alpert 1100-1101; 1 sound cassette
  - Rubin et les Juifs, June 7, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0600; Recording location: Berkeley.; Alpert 1102-1103; 1 sound cassette
  - Friends - Kaplan, Capoeira UCLA; Friends - Kaplan Romain Bday Message, 1984-February 20, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0601; Recording location: UCLA; Alpert 1104-1105; 1 sound cassette
  - Gerry Festival, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0602; Recording location: BRJCC.; Alpert 1106-1107; 1 sound cassette
  - LA Radio, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0604; Alpert 1110; 1 sound cassette
  - Vancouver, Yolocamba Ita, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0605; Alpert 1111-1112; 1 sound cassette
  - Bora, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0609; Personnel: Bora Gajicki, Cammi Stasse, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 1119-1120; 1 sound cassette
  - Avram Pengas, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0616; Alpert 1133; 1 sound cassette
  - Avram Pengas II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0646; Alpert 1134-1135; 1 sound cassette
  - Aaron Ganshor re Montreal Musicians, September 14, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0618; Alpert 1137; 1 sound cassette
  - Menashse Gadish; Nava I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0621; Alpert 1142-1143; 1 sound cassette
  - George Caba Session Tape 1, October 4, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0628; Personnel: George Caba.; Alpert 1158; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - George Caba Session Tape 2, October 4, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0629; Personnel: George Caba.; Alpert 1159; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - George Caba Session Tape 3, October 4, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0630; Personnel: George Caba.; Alpert 1160; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - George Caba Session Tape 4, October 4, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0631; Personnel: George Caba.; Alpert 1161; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - Itzhak Perlman at RCMH Rehearsal, July 2, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0632; Personnel: Itzhak Perlman.; Alpert 1162; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - Itzhak Perlman at RCMH Rehearsal, July 2, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0633; Personnel: Itzhak Perlman.; Alpert 1163; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - Itzhak Perlman at RCMH Show, July 2, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0634; Personnel: Itzhak Perlman.; Alpert 1164; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - Itzhak Perlman at RCMH Show, July 2, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0635; Personnel: Itzhak Perlman.; Alpert 1165; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - Itzhak Perlman at RCMH Fixes, July 3, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0636; Personnel: Itzhak Perlman.; Alpert 1166; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - Itzhak Perlman at RCMH Fixes, July 3, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0637; Personnel: Itzhak Perlman.; Alpert 1167; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - Itzhak Perlman Final Mixes, August 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0638; Personnel: Itzhak Perlman.; Alpert 1168; 1 sound cassette (DAT); There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - LA Serbian Victor Jara (KPFK), undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0651; 1 sound cassette
  - Digital surrogates of recordings in Series 7, 1959-2008, afc2017048_dc001; Digital copies of audio are available as both WAV and MP3 files. PDF files depicting the outside of each audio carrier are also available for many of the recordings.; 343 WAV, 343 MP3, 174 PDF
- Series 8: Brave Old World and Michael Alpert's personal recordings
  Recordings of Michael Alpert's klezmer ensemble, Brave Old World, as well as personal performances and rehearsals from Alpert and other klezmer ensembles.
  - Khevrisa Symphony Space I, October 6, 2002, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Symphony Space.; Alpert 272; 1 WAV
  - Khevrisa Symphony Space II, October 6, 2002, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Symphony Space.; Alpert 273; 1 WAV
  - Fuge Imaginea, Danny Elfman birthday party, June 1, 2002, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Stuart Brotman, Miller, Eppler, Kasap, Knight.; Recording location: Los Angeles.; Alpert 276; 1 WAV
  - Fima-AM improv, July 2003, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 285; 1 WAV
  - Greek BOW, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 293; 1 WAV
  - SFB Klezmer Meeting, November 17, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0244; Personnel: Brave Old World.; Alpert 481-482; 1 sound cassette
  - Work Tape, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0317; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 624-625; 1 sound cassette
  - Work Tape, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0318; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 626-627; 1 sound cassette
  - Work Tape, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0319; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 628-629; 1 sound cassette
  - Misha Feygin, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0337; Personnel: Misha Feygin, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 659-660; 1 sound cassette
  - MA New Songs, 1993, AFC 2017/048: SR0343; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 669-670; 1 sound cassette
  - Answering Machine Tape, December 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0401; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 768; 1 sound cassette
  - Brave Old World Concert, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0408; Personnel: Brave Old World.; Alpert 778-779; 1 sound cassette
  - Brave Old World Rehearsal; Practice Tape, February 20-March 3, 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0411; Personnel: Brave Old World.; Alpert 783-784; 1 sound cassette
  - Michael Composing, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0417; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 793; 1 sound cassette
  - Klezmer Madness Rehearsal, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0420; Personnel: David Krakauer, Michael Alpert, David Licht.; Alpert 798; 1 sound cassette
  - Child Playing; Children's Chorus with Alpert, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0421; Alpert 799-800; 1 sound cassette
  - DOV Brainstorm Tape I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0440; Alpert 834; 1 sound cassette
  - PVDOV-Rehearsal Recordings, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0447; Alpert 847-848; 1 sound cassette
  - Joel Rubin Klezmer Band Brave Old World, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0451; Personnel: Joel Rubin, Michael Alpert, Alan Bern, Stuart Brotman.; Alpert 854; 1 sound cassette
  - Michael and Jules Rehearsal, April 18, 2002, AFC 2017/048: SR0463; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Julian Kytasty.; Alpert 877-878; 1 sound cassette
  - Michael and Jules Rehearsal, April 25, 2002, AFC 2017/048: SR0464; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Julian Kytasty.; Alpert 879-880; 1 sound cassette
  - Me-They Can't Put It Back, etc., undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0467; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 884-885; 1 sound cassette
  - Work Tape, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0468; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 886-887; 1 sound cassette
  - Lecture Tape - Work Tape, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0469; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 888-889; 1 sound cassette
  - Work Tape, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0470; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 890-891; 1 sound cassette
  - Late 1984 and 1985, Work, 1984-1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0471; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 892-893; 1 sound cassette
  - Work Tape, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0472; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 894-895; 1 sound cassette
  - New Songs, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0474; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 898-899; 1 sound cassette
  - New Songs, 1992-1993, AFC 2017/048: SR0475; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 900-901; 1 sound cassette
  - New Songs, 1994-1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0476; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 902-903; 1 sound cassette
  - New Songs, December 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0477; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 904; 1 sound cassette
  - MA Originals, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0478; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 905-906; 1 sound cassette
  - Practice Tape and Europe, June 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0480; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 908; 1 sound cassette
  - MA Originals, 1999-2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0481; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 909-910; 1 sound cassette
  - MA Originals, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0482; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Alan Bern, Kurt Bjorling, Stuart Brotman.; Alpert 911-912; 1 sound cassette
  - MA Guitar Accompange, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0483; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 913-914; 1 sound cassette
  - Fiddle Work Tape, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0484; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 915-916; 1 sound cassette
  - Kapelye Listening Tape I-V, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0485; Alpert 917-918; 1 sound cassette
  - Exile with Brotman, Leslie's Tape; Stu's Birthday Tape, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0486; Personnel: Stuart Brotman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 919-920; 1 sound cassette
  - My Own Stuff-I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0488; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 923-924; 1 sound cassette
  - Interview of MA, November 15, 1994, AFC 2017/048: SR0513; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 982-983; 1 sound cassette
  - Mark and Me, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0517; Alpert 990-991; 1 sound cassette
  - BOW Concert, DRS Radio, July 6, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0531; Alpert 1012-1013; 1 sound cassette
  - Brave New World at New York Historical Society-I, May 9, 1992, AFC 2017/048: SR0532; Recording location: New York Historical Society, New York, NY.; Alpert 1014-1015; 1 sound cassette
  - Brave New World at New York Historical Society-II, May 9, 1992, AFC 2017/048: SR0533; Recording location: New York Historical Society, New York, NY.; Alpert 1016-1017; 1 sound cassette
  - Michael Alpert and Kurt Bjorling on Radio Gumbo, March 20, 1993, AFC 2017/048: SR0535; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Kurt Bjorling, Stuart Rosenberg.; Recording location: Radio Gambo Studios, Chicago.; Alpert 1020; 1 sound cassette
  - Brave Old World, Interview on Multi Kulti-I, November 20, 1994, AFC 2017/048: SR0645; Alpert 1021-1022; 1 sound cassette
  - Brave Old World, Interview on Multi Kulti - II, November 20, 1994, AFC 2017/048: SR0536; Alpert 1023-1024; 1 sound cassette
  - Brave Old World at Bloomington, Indiana, July 11, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0537; Alpert 1025-1026; 1 sound cassette
  - BOW-Wuppertal, November 11, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0538; Alpert 1027-1028; 1 sound cassette
  - BOW at KITO, February 22, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0539; Alpert 1029-1030; 1 sound cassette
  - BOW - Blood Oranges, Unmixed Takes-I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0542; Alpert 1035-1036; 1 sound cassette
  - BOW-Blood Oranges, Unmixed Takes-III, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0543; Alpert 1037-1038; 1 sound cassette
  - Rehearsal, January 26, 2003, AFC 2017/048: SR0554; Alpert 1051; 1 minidisc
  - [Brave Old World interview], undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0591; Alpert 1088; 1 minidisc
  - Young Michael LA, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0614; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Los Angeles.; Alpert 1129-1130; 1 sound cassette
  - Rehearsal Tape, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0619; Alpert 1138-1139; 1 sound cassette
  - [Michael Alpert singing], April 2003, AFC 2017/048: SR0640; Alpert 1171-1172; 1 sound cassette (microcassette)
  - Tunes, September 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0643; Alpert 1177; 1 sound cassette (microcassette)
  - Alpert/Woerden/Warschauer Trio, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0648; 1 sound cassette
  - Bella Gottesman/MJA Accordion, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0649; 1 sound cassette
  - Digital surrogates for recordings in Series 8, 1982-2003, afc2017048_dc001; Digital copies of audio are available as both WAV and MP3 files. PDF files depicting the outside of each audio carrier are also available for many of the recordings.; 99 WAV, 99 MP3, 41 PDF
- Series 9: Miscellaneous recordings, performances, lectures, and interviews
  Lectures, performances, and interviews presented by individuals beyond his main informants or in unknown locations.
  - Vera Gran and Jerzy Abratowski Orchestra, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0189; Personnel: Vera Gran, Jerzy Abratowski Orchestra.; Alpert 381; 1 sound cassette
  - Yiddish Work Tape, December 6, 1979, AFC 2017/048: SR0296; Personnel, Side A: Frieda Youngstein. Personnel, Side B: Josh Waletzky, Alexander M. Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Bialystoker Home.; Alpert 588-589; 1 sound cassette
  - Zoya Amen, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0363; Personnel: Zoya Amen.; Alpert 707-708; 1 sound cassette
  - Chayele Ash, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0378; Personnel: Chayele Ash.; Alpert 730-731; 1 sound cassette
  - Isaac Aguado, Esther Farhi, Sophie Amira, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0379; Personnel: Isaac Aguado, Esther Farhi, Sophie Amira, Robin Green.; Alpert 732; 1 sound cassette
  - Music for La Serena Songbook, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0380; Alpert 733; 1 sound cassette
  - Preisler Show, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0389; Personnel: Maxmillian Preisler.; Alpert 748-749; 1 sound cassette
  - Swedish and Norwegian Fiddle Music, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0398; Personnel: Väsen.; Alpert 763-764; 1 sound cassette
  - Los Tijuanos de Paraguay, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0400; Alpert 767; 1 sound cassette
  - Violinist, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0404; Alpert 771; 1 sound cassette
  - Bluegrass and Country Compilation LP; Unknown, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0406; Alpert 774-775; 1 sound cassette
  - Oy Vey Children's tape, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0422; Alpert 801-802; 1 sound cassette
  - The Hammered Dulcimer; The Hammered Dulcimer Strikes Again, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0423; Alpert 803-804; 1 sound cassette
  - South African 45s, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0424; Alpert 805-806; 1 sound cassette
  - Leah Israelit, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0434; Personnel: Leah Israelit.; Alpert 824; 1 sound cassette
  - 78s from Marty, March 31, 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0441; Alpert 835-836; 1 sound cassette
  - Rachael Salamander Interview, July 5, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0445; Personnel: Rachel Salamander, Norman Laster; Alpert 843-844; 1 sound cassette
  - Men's Singing-III, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0448; Alpert 849-850; 1 sound cassette
  - Jewish and Other Favorites, Sephardic, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0449; Alpert 851; 1 sound cassette
  - Marks Umthakathi, Amagugu; Amagugu, Luba Guitars, Cothoza Mfana, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0452; Personnel: Marks Umthakathi, Amagugu.; Alpert 855-856; 1 sound cassette
  - Scotland, Gaelic Radio, July 4, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0454; Alpert 859-860; 1 sound cassette
  - Additional nigunim from Sruli, February 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0479; Personnel: Sruli.; Alpert 907; 1 sound cassette
  - Popular Chassidic-Israeli Songs, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0498; Personnel: Pete Sokolow.; Alpert 955-956; 1 sound cassette
  - Annie Goldfarb's Jewish 78s, December 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0510; Alpert 977-978; 1 sound cassette
  - Accordion and Clarinet, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0511; Personnel: Michael Alpert, E. Almosnino.; Alpert 979; 1 sound cassette
  - Town Crier-Chosen, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0512; Alpert 980-981; 1 sound cassette
  - Hasidic Source Tape from Sam Weiss, January 1993, AFC 2017/048: SR0515; Personnel: Sam Weiss.; Alpert 986-987; 1 sound cassette
  - Stu, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0519; Personnel: Stuart Brotman.; Alpert 993; 1 sound cassette
  - [Unlabeled tape with Klezmer music performed on clarinet], undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0561; Alpert 1058; 1 minidisc
  - [Unlabeled tape with songs in English], January 2, 2003, AFC 2017/048: SR0584; Alpert 1061; 1 sound cassette
  - [Songs in various languages], undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0570; Alpert 1069; 1 minidisc
  - Singing Table Rehearsal, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0579; Alpert 1078; 1 sound cassette
  - Singing Table Rehearsal, April 24, 2002, AFC 2017/048: SR0581; Personnel: Lisa Mayer, Sruli Dresner, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 1080; 1 minidisc
  - [Rehearsal with Ensemble Theresa], May 13, 2002, AFC 2017/048: SR0582; Personnel: David Krakauer.; Alpert 1081; 1 minidisc
  - [Unlabeled rehearsal tape], undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0586; Alpert 1083; 1 minidisc
  - Yiddish for Chava, Seymour Levitan, July 1981, AFC 2017/048: SR0598; Alpert 1098-1099; 1 sound cassette
  - Yiddish Traditional Singing, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0608; Alpert 1117-1118; 1 sound cassette
  - Prsut and Pickled Herring-I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0610; Alpert 1121-1122; 1 sound cassette
  - Avry Sharon I; Avry Sharon II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0615; Personnel: Avry Sharon.; Alpert 1131-1132; 1 sound cassette
  - Deb Kayman, Jesus Rosario, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0617; Alpert 1136; 1 sound cassette
  - Vocal Exercises, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0623; Alpert 1146-1147; 1 sound cassette
  - R'Betsalel Althoys-Nigunim, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0624; Personnel: Rabbi Betsalel Althoys.; Alpert 1152-1153; 1 sound cassette
  - Bora-Gocino, Uzicko, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0625; Alpert 1154-1155; 1 sound cassette
  - Yiddishland; My Nigunim, February 2004, AFC 2017/048: SR0641; Alpert 1173-1174; 1 sound cassette (microcassette)
  - Unlabeled, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0650; 1 sound cassette
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in English and Klezmer music performances, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Alpert 1178; 1 WAV
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in English and Klezmer music performances, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Alpert 1179; 1 WAV
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0439; Alpert 833; 1 sound cassette (microcassette)
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0556; Alpert 1053; 1 minidisc
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0558; Alpert 1055; 1 minidisc
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0559; Alpert 1056; 1 minidisc
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0564; Alpert 1063; 1 minidisc
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0565; Alpert 1065; 1 minidisc
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0566; Alpert 1066; 1 minidisc
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0568; Alpert 1067; 1 minidisc
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0569; Alpert 1068; 1 minidisc
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0575; Alpert 1074; 1 minidisc
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0578; Alpert 1077; 1 minidisc
  - Unlabeled recording with interviews in Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0583; Alpert 1060; 1 minidisc